
[
{
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Who was the first woman created by God?",
    "answers": {
        "a": "A. Rachel",
        "b": "B. Sarah",
        "c": "C. Eve",
        "d": "D. Leah"
    },
    "correct": "c"
},
  {
    "id" : 2,
    "question": "Who built an ark to survive the flood?",
    "answers": {
        "a" : "A. Abraham",
        "b" : "B. Isaac",
        "c" : "C. Jacob",
        "d" : "D. Noah"
    },
    "correct": "d"
  },
  {
    "id" : 3,
    "question": "What did God did on the seventh day?",
    "answers": {
        "a" : "A. Animals",
        "b" : "B. Light",
        "c" : "C. Man",
        "d" :  "D. Rest"
    },
    "correct": "d"
  },
  {
    "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the son of Abraham and Sarah?",
    "answers": {
      "a" :"A. Esau",
      "b" : "B. Ishmael",
      "c" : "C. Isaac",
      "d" : "D. Jacob"
    },
    "correct": "c"
  },
  {
    "id" : 5,
    "question": "Who received the Ten Commandments from God?",
    "answers": {
      "a" : "A. Aaron",
      "b" : "B. Moses",
      "c" : "C. Joshua",
      "d" : "D. Caleb"
    },
    "correct": "b"
  },
  {
    "id" : 6,
    "question": "What sea did the Israelites cross to escape from Egypt?",
    "answers": {
      "a" : "A. Dead Sea",
      "b" : "B. Sea of Galilee",
      "c" : "C. Red Sea",
      "d" : "D. Mediterranean Sea"
    },
    "correct": "c"
  },
  {
    "id" : 7,
    "question": "What food did God provide from heaven for the Israelites?",
    "answers": {
      "a" : "A. Bread",
      "b" : "B. Fish",
      "c" : "C. Fruit",
      "d" : "D. Manna"
    },
    "correct": "d"
  },
  {
    "id" : 8,
    "question": "Who was Moses' sister who watched over him as a baby?",
    "answers": {
      "a" : "A. Leah",
      "b" : "B. Miriam",
      "c" : "C. Rachel",
      "d" : "D. Sarah"
    },
    "correct": "a"
  },
  {
    "id" : 9,
    "question": "What was the purpose of the sacrifices detailed in Leviticus?",
    "answers": {
      "a" : "A. Decoration",
      "b" : "B. Celebration",
      "c" : "C. Atonement for sins",
      "d" : "D. Trade"
    },
    "correct": "c"
  },
  {
    "id" : 10,
    "question": "Which tribe was appointed as priests in Israel?",
    "answers": {
      "a" : "A. Judah",
      "b" : "B. Ephraim",
      "c" :  "C. Benjamin",
      "d" : "D Levi"
    },
    "correct": "d"
  },
  {
    "id" : 11,
    "question": "What was not allowed to be offered as a burnt offering?",
    "answers": {
      "a" : "A. Male animals",
      "b" : "B. Birds",
      "c" : "C. Animals with defects",
      "d" : "D. Animals without blemish"
    },
    "correct": "c"
  },
  {
  "id" : 12,
    "question": "How many spies were sent to Canaan?",
    "answers": {
      "a" : "A. 12",
      "b" : "B. 10",
      "c" : "C. 5",
       "d" :"D. 15"
      },
    "correct": "a"
  },
  {
  "id" : 13,
    "question": "Who rebelled against Moses' leadership?",
    "answers": {
      "a" : "A. Korah",
      "b" : "B. Caleb",
      "c" : "C. Aaron",
      "d" : "D. Joshua"
    },
    "correct": "a"
  },
  {
  "id" : 14,
    "question": "What was the symbol of God's presence and guidance?",
    "answers": {
      "a" : "A. A dove",
      "b" : "B. A cloud",
      "c" : "C. A mountain",
      "d" : "D. A stone"
    },
    "correct": "b"
  },
  {
  "id" : 15,
    "question": "Where did Moses strike a rock to bring water?",
    "answers" : {
      "a" : "A. Bethel",
      "b" : "B. Jericho",
      "c" : "C. Sinai",
      "d" : "D. Meribah"
    },
    "correct": "d"
  },
  {
  "id" : 16,
    "question": "Which commandment emphasizes honoring parents?",
    "answers": {
      "a" : "A. First",
      "b" :  "B. Fifth",
      "c" : "C. Seventh",
      "d" : "D. Tenth"
    },
    "correct": "b"
  },
  {
  "id" : 17,
    "question": "What does Deuteronomy mean?",
    "answers" : {
      "a" : "A. Second Law",
      "b" :  "B. First Law",
      "c" : "C. New Beginning",
      "d" : "D. Story of Moses"
    },
    "correct": "a"
  },
  {
  "id" : 18,
    "question": "Which mountain did Moses view the Promised Land from?",
    "answers": {
      "a" : "A. Sinai",
      "b" : "B. Horeb",
      "c" : "C. Nebo",
      "d" : "D. Carmel"
    },
    "correct": "c"
  },
  {
  "id" : 19,
    "question": "What did Moses warn the Israelites against?",
    "answers" : {
      "a" : "A. Being lazy",
      "b" : "B. Idolatry",
      "c" : "C. Speaking other languages",
      "d" : "D. Fasting"
    },
    "correct": "b"
  },
  {
  "id" : 20,
    "question": "Who succeeded Moses as the leader of Israel?",
    "answers" : {
      "a" : "A. Caleb", "David", "Joshua",
       "Solomon"
    },
    "correct": "Joshua"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "What city did the Israelites march around for seven days to conquer?",
    "answers"{: ["Jericho", "Ai", "Bethlehem", "Heb}ron"],
    "correct": "Jericho"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who hid the Israelite spies in Jericho?",
    "answers"{: ["Miriam", "Rahab", "Deborah", "Est}her"],
    "correct": "Rahab"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "What was the sign of the covenant between God and Israel after their victory?",
    "answers"{: ["A rainbow", "A stone", "A pillar }of fire", "The sun standing still"],
    "correct": "The sun standing still"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the judge who defeated Sisera with the help of a woman?",
    "answers"{: ["Gideon", "Samson", "Deborah", "Je}phthah"],
    "correct": "Deborah"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who defeated the Midianites with only 300 men?",
    "answers"{: ["Samson", "Gideon", "David", "Saul}"],
    "correct": "Gideon"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "What was the name of the strong judge who was betrayed by Delilah?",
    "answers"{: ["Samson", "Jephthah", "Abimelech",} "Othniel"],
    "correct": "Samson"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Which judge made a vow to offer the first thing that came out of his house?",
    "answers"{: ["Jephthah", "Gideon", "Samson", "B}arak"],
    "correct": "Jephthah"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was Ruth's mother-in-law?",
    "answers"{: ["Hannah", "Deborah", "Naomi", "Sar}ah"],
    "correct": "Naomi"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Where did Ruth meet Boaz?",
    "answers"{: ["In the field", "At the well", "At} the market", "At the temple"],
    "correct": "In the field"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was Ruth's first husband?",
    "answers"{: ["Boaz", "Elimelech", "Mahlon", "Na}omi's son"],
    "correct": "Mahlon"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "What was Ruth's nationality?",
    "answers"{: ["Israelite", "Moabite", "Philistin}e", "Egyptian"],
    "correct": "Moabite"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the first king of Israel?",
    "answers"{: ["David", "Saul", "Solomon", "Samue}l"],
    "correct": "Saul"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who defeated Goliath?",
    "answers"{: ["Saul", "David", "Solomon", "Joshu}a"],
    "correct": "David"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who anointed David as king?",
    "answers"{: ["Samuel", "Nathan", "Gad", "Elijah}"],
    "correct": "Samuel"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "What did Saul offer to the person who killed Goliath?",
    "answers"{: ["Riches", "His daughter's hand in }marriage", "A house", "Land"],
    "correct": "His daughter's hand in marriage"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the son of David who rebelled against him?",
    "answers"{: ["Absalom", "Solomon", "Rehoboam", }"Adonijah"],
    "correct": "Absalom"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "What did David bring to Jerusalem to make it a holy city?",
    "answers"{: ["The Ark of the Covenant", "The Te}mple", "The Tabernacle", "The Golden Calf"],
    "correct": "The Ark of the Covenant"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was David's best friend and son of Saul?",
    "answers"{: ["Jonathan", "Samuel", "Abner", "Na}than"],
    "correct": "Jonathan"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the wise king who built the temple in Jerusalem?",
    "answers"{: ["David", "Solomon", "Rehoboam", "J}eroboam"],
    "correct": "Solomon"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "What did Solomon ask for when God offered to give him anything?",
    "answers"{: ["Wealth", "Long life", "Wisdom", "}Power over enemies"],
    "correct": "Wisdom"
  },  

  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who challenged the prophets of Baal on Mount Carmel?",
    "answers"{: ["Elijah", "Elisha", "Isaiah", "Jer}emiah"],
    "correct": "Elijah"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Which prophet was swallowed by a big fish?",
    "answers"{: ["Daniel", "Jonah", "Ezekiel", "Hos}ea"],
    "correct": "Jonah"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the prophet that succeeded Elijah?",
    "answers"{: ["Elisha", "Isaiah", "Jeremiah", "M}alachi"],
    "correct": "Elisha"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the king of Israel that built the golden calves?",
    "answers"{: ["Solomon", "Saul", "Jeroboam", "Ah}ab"],
    "correct": "Jeroboam"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Which prophet is known for the vision of dry bones coming to life?",
    "answers"{: ["Isaiah", "Jeremiah", "Ezekiel", "}Daniel"],
    "correct": "Ezekiel"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Which king had a dream about a statue made of different metals?",
    "answers"{: ["David", "Solomon", "Nebuchadnezza}r", "Cyrus"],
    "correct": "Nebuchadnezzar"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was thrown into the fiery furnace for refusing to worship the golden image?",
    "answers"{: ["Shadrach", "Meshach", "Abednego",} "Daniel"],
    "correct": "Shadrach, Meshach, and Abednego"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the Persian king that allowed the Israelites to return to Jerusalem?",
    "answers"{: ["Darius", "Cyrus", "Artaxerxes", "}Xerxes"],
    "correct": "Cyrus"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the prophet that confronted King Ahab and Queen Jezebel?",
    "answers"{: ["Elijah", "Isaiah", "Hosea", "Amos}"],
    "correct": "Elijah"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Which prophet predicted the coming of a Messiah who would suffer for the sins of the people?",
    "answers"{: ["Isaiah", "Jeremiah", "Micah", "Ze}chariah"],
    "correct": "Isaiah"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was swallowed by a great fish after fleeing from God's command?",
    "answers"{: ["Jonah", "Noah", "Elijah", "Daniel}"],
    "correct": "Jonah"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the queen of Persia who saved the Jewish people?",
    "answers"{: ["Esther", "Ruth", "Deborah", "Miri}am"],
    "correct": "Esther"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the first man to be called a 'prophet' in the Bible?",
    "answers"{: ["Abraham", "Moses", "Samuel", "Eli}jah"],
    "correct": "Abraham"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the last prophet in the Old Testament?",
    "answers"{: ["Isaiah", "Malachi", "Haggai", "Ze}chariah"],
    "correct": "Malachi"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "What is the shortest verse in the Bible?",
    "answers"{: ["Jesus wept.", "God is love.", "In} the beginning.", "For God so loved the world."],
    "correct": "Jesus wept."
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the Roman governor who sentenced Jesus to be crucified?",
    "answers"{: ["Pilate", "Caesar", "Herod", "Fest}us"],
    "correct": "Pilate"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "What was the name of the disciple who denied Jesus three times?",
    "answers"{: ["James", "John", "Peter", "Thomas"}],
    "correct": "Peter"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the disciple known for doubting Jesus' resurrection until he saw Him?",
    "answers"{: ["Peter", "Thomas", "James", "Andre}w"],
    "correct": "Thomas"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "What was the name of the place where Jesus was crucified?",
    "answers"{: ["Mount Zion", "Golgotha", "Bethleh}em", "Mount Sinai"],
    "correct": "Golgotha"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who betrayed Jesus with a kiss?",
    "answers"{: ["Peter", "Judas", "Matthew", "John}"],
    "correct": "Judas"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the first Christian martyr?",
    "answers"{: ["James", "Stephen", "Paul", "John"}],
    "correct": "Stephen"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who wrote most of the New Testament letters?",
    "answers"{: ["Peter", "John", "Paul", "James"],}
    "correct": "Paul"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Which book comes last in the New Testament?",
    "answers"{: ["Revelation", "Jude", "John", "Act}s"],
    "correct": "Revelation"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the first Gentile convert to Christianity?",
    "answers"{: ["Cornelius", "Lydia", "Eunice", "T}itus"],
    "correct": "Cornelius"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "What event marks the beginning of the Christian Church?",
    "answers"{: ["The Resurrection", "The Ascension}", "Pentecost", "The Last Supper"],
    "correct": "Pentecost"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "What was the first miracle performed by Jesus?",
    "answers"{: ["Healing a blind man", "Turning wa}ter into wine", "Feeding the 5000", "Walking on water"],
    "correct": "Turning water into wine"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "What did Jesus teach about loving your enemies?",
    "answers"{: ["Pray for them", "Hate them", "Ign}ore them", "Defeat them"],
    "correct": "Pray for them"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "What did Jesus say was the greatest commandment?",
    "answers"{: ["Love God", "Love your neighbor", }"Honor your parents", "Keep the Sabbath holy"],
    "correct": "Love God"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who was the first to witness Jesus' resurrection?",
    "answers"{: ["Mary Magdalene", "Peter", "John",} "Thomas"],
    "correct": "Mary Magdalene"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Which apostle was known for being a tax collector before following Jesus?",
    "answers"{: ["Matthew", "Luke", "Mark", "John"]},
    "correct": "Matthew"
  },
  {
  "id" : 4,
    "question": "Who wrote the book of Revelation?",
    "answers"{: ["Paul", "John", "Peter", "James"],}
    "correct": "John"
  }
]  